Paul Zeng



OBJECTIVE

Passionate web developer with a flair for creating elegant solutions in the least amount of time. Experienced 9 years in full stack and mobile app development including a blockchain gaming project, wallet desktop app, ecommerce webapp, customer web portal, ERP systems, and donations webapp for a local charity. Passionate about software architecture and cloud computing.



EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science | Hong Kong University of Science and technology SEP 2009 – AUG 2013



EXPERIENCE

Front end developer | DBS Bank

JUN 2022 - SEP 2023

Built a Damselfy project with frontend team.

- Attended scrum meeting for daily updates and tasks
- Write frontend code using React, styled-components
- Added multi-lang support to the project
- Added test code using jest and increased coverage to 85%
- Tested features on SIT and delivered it to testers to verify

Front end Developer | XTZSports

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022

Built a Zone GameFi platform using blockchain.

- Developed the frontend from Figma design using React, Next.js, Styled-components
- Integrated with Algorand blockchain (Pera Wallet and MyAlgo)

Front end Lead | ROG Security, Inc.

DEC 2019 - APR 2021

- Built an IP Camera Thread Detection web app to allow admins monitor camera screens and draw areas to protect parts and notify when user comes
- Fixed all the bugs in Asana and improved the web app performance
- Oversaw full lifecycle of software development and guided other 2 developers

Full Stack Developer | Crowdbotics

NOV 2013 - NOV 2019

Delivered 5 projects on time while staying 10% under budget

- Developed virtual zoo website using MERN stack, QA testing on different platforms using Browserstack, optimized the application to keep it reactive with thousands of users.
- Developed backend pusher app of the International Friends community in Germany
- Developed healthcare projects (Boring ai) using Laravel, Vue.js, managed CI/CD using Laravel Forge, integrated payment gateway.



SKILLS

- Javascript, Typescript, React, Vue
- Material-UI, Ant Design, Grommet
- Bootstrap, TailwindCSS, SASS
- PHP, Laravel, Codelgniter
- Java, .NET
- Node, Python, Django
- Data Visualization, D3, Fabric.js, Chart.js
- Jest, Enzyme
- MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- GraphQL, Apollo, Firebase
- Agile, Scrum, Git
- Docker, AWS, Google Cloud, Azure